Guide to the Zion Episcopal Church of Palmyra records,1823-1917.
Zion Episcopal Church of Palmyra records,1823-1917.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Zion Episcopal Church of Palmyra records, 1823-1917.
6024
Zion Episcopal Church of Palmyra (Palmyra, N.Y.)
1 reel microfilm.
Microfilm
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Baptismal and membership records for 1823-1895, one volume of vestry minutes (1827-1917) with entries on official church functions, financial matters and elections, and a sreies of annual sermons (1852-1861).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The records of Zion Episcopal Church of Palmyra document the activities of the church administration and give statistical information concerning the parishioners. Included in the collection is one volume (1823- 95) containing information on marriages, baptisms, confirmations, burials, communicants, and newspaper coverage of parish events. One volume of vestry minutes (1827-1917) contains entries of official church functions, financial matters and notes of elections to various offices. A third group of records is a series of annual sermons from 1852-61.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Zion Episcopal Church of Palmyra (Palmyra, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Episcopal Church--New York (State)--Palmyra.
Places:
Palmyra (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Wayne County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Baptismal certificates.; Minutes.; Sermons.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
NOTE: Collection microfilmed out of order.
CONTAINER LIST
- Sermond Books, 1851-61, all 32 pages., Item #3
  (first on reel)
  - book 1
    Discourse for 1851. Text: "Though I be absent in the flesh, yet am I with you in the spirit." pp. 31-2 contains a list of Parochial Acts for 1857-61 with statistics for baptisms, communicants, confirmations, marriages, weekday services, and communion services.
  - book 2
    Annual discourse for 1852 on the history of the church.
  - book 3
    Annual discourse for 1853.
  - book 4
    Annual discourse for 1854.
  - book 5
    Annual discourse for 1855.
  - book 6
    Annual discourse for 1856, containing instructions of record keeping.
  - book 7
    The condition of the parish viewed spiritually, an address at Lent, 1856.
  - book 8
    Annual discourse for 1857.
  - book 9
    Annual discourse for 1858.
  - book 10
    Annual discourse for 1859.
  - book 11
    Annual discourse for 1860.
  - book 12
    Annual discourse for l86l.
- Parish Record of Zion Church, Item #1
  - clippings with a list of pastors, 1823-1895.
  - infant and adult baptisms, 1823-72.
  - confirmations, 1831-71.
  - communicants, 1826-75.
    (Until 1827 names are listed, thereafter it is indicated whether the person died, was removed or suspended. The 1833 list indicated residences).
  - burials, 1828-72.
    Name, age, whether infant, and if so, parent's names are indicated.
  - ordinations, l834, 43.
  - clippings.
- Vestry Records, 1832-1917, Chronological, paginated., Item #2
  Minutes of the vestry, wardens, and congregation's meetings contain attendance and subscription records, reports of the election of the wardens and vestrymen, planning and building new churches, appointment of sub-committees, employment of pastors, and financial information.